<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>D ∆ V E E S T E S</title>
    <atom:link href="estes.tk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>estes.tk</link>
    <description>-.-.- </description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>CMHA Logo x DESIGN</title>
      <link>estes.tk/articles/cmha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">estes.tk/articles/cmha/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/cmha/LOGO1small.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;logo-re-design-for-the-ct-morgan-horse-association-&quot;&gt;Logo re-design for the CT Morgan Horse Association.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/cmha/old.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;old-logo-classic-but-needed-an-update-&quot;&gt;Old logo. Classic but needed an update.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;centertext&quot;&gt;
I was tasked with re-designing a logo for the CT Morgan Horse Association. Let me tell you something about me.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I don’t like horses.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I don’t have anything against them personally. I’ve never been bamboozled by a horse. I just don’t trust them. They are too big and muscular. I like them in theory but I’ve been ruined by watching videos online of cowboys get kicked in the head.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This led to some interesting discoveries on my part. Apparently there are different kinds of horses.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Initially I though “I’ll just make an elegant, simple horse head. Something with a painterly feel that kind of vibes with the New England horse community.” So I created a logo after looking up pictures of horses on Google.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;firstdraftcmha.png&quot; width=50%&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;first-draft-it-looks-like-a-horse-just-not-the-right-kind-of-horse-&quot;&gt;First draft. It looks like a horse… just not the right kind of horse.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;centertext&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Did you know different breeds of horses have different shaped heads?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They do. I didn’t know that going in. That’s ok, it’s an easy fix.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;firstdraftcmha2.png&quot; width=50%&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;boom-morgan-horse-&quot;&gt;Boom. Morgan horse.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/cmha/LOGO3small.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just the logo. Nice and clean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;leftcol&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/articles/cmha/1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot;&gt; &lt;br&gt; In the end we wound up with a clean, simple, elegant vector logo that can be used in horse shows or any kind of advertising.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;rightcol&quot;&gt; Slap it on a shirt or something. &lt;br&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/articles/cmha/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;3.png&quot; width=50%&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
Cup of coffee.
DE&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pheye Nebula x DESIGN</title>
      <link>estes.tk/articles/Rawberry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">estes.tk/articles/Rawberry/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/Rawberry/Nebula.png&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-is-a-selection-of-my-design-work-&quot;&gt;Here is a selection of my design work.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pheye Labs x DESIGN</title>
      <link>estes.tk/articles/PheyeLabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">estes.tk/articles/PheyeLabs/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/PheyeLabs/9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;branding-product-and-marketing-solutions-for-pheye-labs-&quot;&gt;Branding, product, and marketing solutions for Pheye Labs.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;pheye-labs-is-a-manufacturer-of-e-juice-in-connecticut-&quot;&gt;Pheye Labs is a manufacturer of E-juice in Connecticut.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electronic cigarettes were like the wild west.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the electronic cigarette market first took off, it was complete wild west. It was completely new industry with no precedent on how to approach the marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a really fun endeavor as I got to handle the branding, marketing, and product design almost completely independently. This was also a huge learning experience because before this, I had only ever done design for digital media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The bottle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/PheyeLabs/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Pheye Labs was going for a heady, futuristic look but it also needed to look clean. The product was something that people were going to be putting in their body and needed to appeal to the customer in a way that made them feel confident in it’s quality. It was made in lab conditions and we had to come up with a look that played well with that. It also could be dangerous if children got their hands on it so we needed to make sure it didn’t look like something a kid would like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/PheyeLabs/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/PheyeLabs/12.png&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;so-we-went-for-a-space-medicine-look-&quot;&gt;So we went for a “Space Medicine” look.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;leftcol&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;leftcol&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/articles/PheyeLabs/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;rightcol&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/articles/PheyeLabs/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;righttcol&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;leftcol&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/articles/PheyeLabs/10.png&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;rightcol&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/articles/PheyeLabs/11.png&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pheye Nebula x DESIGN</title>
      <link>estes.tk/articles/PheyeNebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">estes.tk/articles/PheyeNebula/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/PheyeNebula/Nebula.png&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-is-a-selection-of-my-design-work-&quot;&gt;Here is a selection of my design work.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>/README</title>
      <link>estes.tk/articles/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">estes.tk/articles/hello-world/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/hello-world/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-went-to-your-website-and-it-was-down-&quot;&gt;I went to your website and it was down.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve gone through about 9 different personal portfolio sites and about 6 different domain names. This is one of those sites. Here’s how I’m going to do this one a little bit differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-experiment&quot;&gt;The experiment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site is currently hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.io&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. The end goal of this site is to create a permanant and resillient portolio of my work. I am planning on doing this through the eventual use of &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io/&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt; and possibly utilizing a blockchain to handle DNS. Hopefully this will allow me to have my work in a permanent location that I can continue to point people to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools-&quot;&gt;Tools:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wintersmith: Static site generator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github: Hosting solution until IPFS implimentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;IPFS: peer-to-peer method of storing and sharing hypermedia in a distributed file system.&lt;/del&gt; Not yet implimented.
+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;considerations&quot;&gt;Considerations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real experiment here for me is to see if I can find a solution that checks all of the boxes below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Cost - Control - Ease of use - Resilliancy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost&lt;/strong&gt; : I am looking to do this for free. This one is simple. This should not be too hard as there are plenty of solutions out there that offer free web hosting. These have their caveats which are addressed below. For right now I am using a .tk domain (free).Coincidentally this is the same ccTLD that I used when I first got into web design and fiddling with websites about 16 years ago. I went from that to owning about 10 domain names. Funny how it has come full circle for the sake of science and frugality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control&lt;/strong&gt; : A domain is one thing but hosting is a where you really run into issues with this. Most free solutions come at the cost of having very little control over both the asthetic and security of your data. I believe I will be able find a solution that allows me to keep total control over my site and not have to give up my data in exchange for free hosting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ease of Use&lt;/strong&gt; : Any solution that is viable would need to be accessable by anyone using a “regular” browser. This is mainly an issue of implimentation and will need to be explored as we get into a more complicated setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resilliancy&lt;/strong&gt; : I am the type of person who will go wild on a website and then let it sit for 6 months. When I come back to it I still need it to be there. If I can set this up for free and host it correctly, the goal is a website I can set and forget. What I am trying to explore is the possibility of building a portfolio site that my kids can go back to and read long after I’m gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s see where this takes us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pheye Labs x DESIGN</title>
      <link>estes.tk/articles/PheyeLabs%20(copy)/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">estes.tk/articles/PheyeLabs%20(copy)/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our written testimony: OPPOSITION TO PROPOSED BILL NO. 6283, AN ACT REGULATING ELECTRONIC CIGARETTES
Posted on February 17, 2015 by PheyeLabs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as many CT residents may be aware, there is a horrible new vaping bill that has reared it’s ugly head. We are submitting this written testimony in the hopes that it will help vocalize our specific issues with this bill. We encourage you to write your state reps and also call. The more vocal we are against this bill, the less likely it is to pass!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pheye Labs LLC Testimony to Joint Committee on Public Health&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IN OPPOSITION TO PROPOSED BILL NO. 6283,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AN ACT REGULATING ELECTRONIC CIGARETTES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are Pheye Labs LLC, a small two person company that manufactures flavored e-juice for use in electronic cigarettes. We would like to thank you for the opportunity to comment on this proposed legislation and to weigh in with our thoughts on the matter. This law will directly impact ourselves as well as the many vapers and vape shops around the state. As vapers ourselves we also have concerns with how this law will affect the quality and availability of electronic cigarette products here in CT. Our goal as members of the vaping community is to help our lawmakers understand that without the affordable and available alternative to smoking that vaping provides, countless CT residents will return to smoking. As you well know, this is a death sentence for those that do. This proposed legislation, while well intentioned, will have extremely negative consequences for the residents of CT who choose to use electronic cigarettes as an alternative to smoking.  We would like to address the specific issues we have with this proposed legislation point by point as this bill is very broad and affects many different areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That the general statutes be amended to require&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1) electronic cigarettes to be (A) defined as a tobacco product:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electronic cigarettes vaporize a mixture of USP grade Vegetable Glycerin (VG), USP grade Propylene Glycol (PG), and food grade flavorings.They can also contain nicotine ranging from 3mg/ml to 24mg/ml. Nowhere in any electronic cigarette is there any form of tobacco in it’s whole form. The nicotine that is added into the e-juice is a chemically pure molecule that is suspended in VG or PG. Any tobacco flavored e-juice is created by adding artificial and natural flavoring compounds to a mix of PG and VG to try and replicate the taste of a cigarette. So the first issue with classifying electronic cigarettes as a tobacco products is that they do not contain tobacco. Electronic cigarettes are no more a tobacco product due to the nicotine added than soda is a coffee product due to the caffeine added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have heard the argument that because electronic cigarettes can contain nicotine derived from tobacco then electronic cigarettes are therefor tobacco products. The issue with this line of logic is that there is a considerable amount of people who use electronic cigarettes containing no nicotine. People who have quit smoking but still occasionally struggle with the oral fixation of smoking make up a large amount of zero nicotine electronic cigarette users. This provides them with a nicotine free alternative to what would otherwise include them relapsing and reintroducing nicotine into their system via a cigarette. A considerable amount of our sales are for e-juice that contains no nicotine. This zero nicotine e-juice is comprised of PG, VG, and flavorings. If one goes into their local baking supply store or Stop &amp;amp; Shop there are many baking flavorings that contain the same exact ingredients you will find in zero nicotine e-juice. While the quality of the ingredients (e-juice uses usp grade or better PG and VG) and the ratios of the ingredients may be different, there is a fundamental overlap of zero nicotine e-juice and baking flavorings. The next time you are in the store, take a look at the ingredients of the liquid baking flavorings. They are functionally and chemically the same liquid except for intended usage, concentration, and quality of ingredients. There are enough people who vape zero nicotine e-juice to warrant this argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electronic cigarettes are not tobacco products. They are a promising and viable cigarette alternative. Classifying them as tobacco products is not only incorrect, it is misleading and irresponsible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(B) subject to the same smoke-free laws as cigarettes, as defined in section 4-28h:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of CT’s smoke free laws seek to protect people from the negative health effects second hand smoke and give people a reasonable expectation to breath clean air when out in public. These are perfectly reasonable laws and help protect the public. However, it has been proven that second hand vapor from electronic cigarettes “…are a source of secondhand exposure to nicotine but not to combustion toxicants. The air concentrations of nicotine emitted by various brands of e-cigarettes ranged from 0.82 to 6.23 µg/m3. The average concentration of nicotine resulting from smoking tobacco cigarettes was 10 times higher than from e-cigarettes (31.60±6.91 vs. 3.32±2.49 µg/m3, respectively; p = .0081).” [1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the fact that the OSHA Permissible Exposure Limit (PEL) standard for nicotine [2] is .5mg/m3 and 6.23µg/m3  (The highest end of nicotine air concentrations from second hand vapor) equals 0.00623mg/m3 , it stands to reason that an air concentration 80 times less than OSHA’s PEL is not a significant threat to the public’s well being. One is exposed to more toxins while driving on RT. 84 than by being exposed to secondhand vapor. Businesses owners should be able look at the facts and decide for themselves how their establishment will regulate electronic cigarette use. Lumping smoking and vaping together is not only unnecessary, it is factually inaccurate. The closer we look, the more differences we discover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(C) subject to the same marketing restrictions as cigarettes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of placing marketing restrictions on cigarettes was to make sure that they were not being targeted to children. Electronic cigarettes are a product intended to be used by adults over the age of 18. It makes sense for their marketing to be targeted to adults. However, in a state where it is illegal to sell electronic cigarettes to people under the age of 18, it really doesn’t make sense for them to market to an illegal target market. Resources could be better spent by enforcing the existing CT law that forbids the sale to minors. The main issue with putting the same marketing restrictions on electronic cigarettes as cigarettes however has to do with restrictions on flavoring. We can address this in the next section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(D) flavorless:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is quite possibly the most important and damaging portion of this proposed legislation. One assumes that by “flavorless” you mean restricting flavorings to only tobacco flavorings. The issue with this is that all e-juice is inherently literally flavorless. It is comprised of VG, PG, and nicotine if applicable. These base chemicals are flavorless and subtly sweet by themselves but are essentially flavorless. Any flavor e-juice, be it tobacco, bakery or fruit are then created by adding flavorings to the base mix of the e-juice. Unlike a cigarette that tastes like a cigarette unless you add flavoring to it, e-juice must be flavored to taste like anything. All e-juice, even tobacco flavored, is still flavored. Most of the tobacco flavorings available on the market do not taste like tobacco because the flavor of a burning cigarette is very hard to replicate without combustion. Most of the tobacco flavored e-juice has more of a nutty note than that of a real cigarette. This is why most people prefer fruit flavored electronic cigarettes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This portion of the legislation is based off of the incorrect assumption that children are the only ones that want or use flavors outside of tobacco flavorings. As an e-juice manufacturer, we have a unique insight into what flavors our customers actually want and why. We have heard it argued that candy/fruit flavors cater to children. We have a strict policy of only selling to adults 18 years or older. All of the shops that carry our juice check ID for each sale. This gives us the ability to look at our sales figures and determine what flavors ADULTS are buying. We have found that our top seller is our fruit flavor “Rawberry” which is a berry blend. After speaking with customers in various vape shops across the state and country we found that a vast majority of vapers mostly purchased fruity flavors followed by bakery (cakes and cookie) type flavors. Most people indicated that they really didn’t enjoy tobacco flavors and chose to distance themselves from the flavors associated with smoking. A vast majority of vapers are ex-smokers. Many slowly lower their nicotine intake until they are weaned off of nicotine altogether. Forcing people to only vape tobacco flavors in a misguided attempt to protect children is the same as saying that a recovering alcoholic can’t purchase a soda because children enjoy sweet drinks. We wouldn’t say that they can only drink Odules. Why then would we use the same line of logic for ex-smokers? The idea is absurd and will only drive people back to smoking cigarettes. If you value the lives of your constituents you should not be forcing them back to their old dangerous habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this state we have alcoholic drinks (another adult product) in every flavor imaginable. The reason for this is not because companies are catering to kids. The reason is that adults are human and enjoy things that taste good. Each person has their own personal taste that they are entitled to. Condemning a person to smoking cigarettes because they enjoy fruity or candy flavored electronic cigarettes is not only unfair it is unnecessary and irresponsible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(E) subject to standards for contaminants and strict quality control of manufacturing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the electronic cigarette industry has done very well at self regulating and keeping our products as safe as possible, it is to be expected that at some point there would be regulations placed on manufacturing. This is a massive undertaking that if done improperly could ruin the industry and force sales into a completely unregulated black market. The FDA is currently researching and working on a set of electronic cigarette regulations that the country would have to abide by. Given the FDA’s massive budget, the country-wide data set from which to draw conclusions, and the top-tier researchers and academics, it would make sense to let the FDA create regulations for the manufacturing of electronic cigarettes. The electronic cigarette industry is already a $2 billion dollar industry that is set to grow exponentially over the coming years. As the industry grows, so will the cost of regulation grow. The burden of this regulation will fall on the CT taxpayers in an already fiscally difficult time. By allowing the FDA to regulate electronic cigarettes it will lead to A) More concise and uniform requirements B) Regulations based on well funded research currently being conducted by the FDA vs. premature notions of what is necessary and C) The ability for manufacturers from other states to create products that can be marketed to the entire country (including CT). The vast majority of vape shops here in CT carry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;products that were made in other states. By creating regulations before the FDA has a chance to deem a country-wide set of standards it will leave most of the vape shops in the state with a full stock of juice they can no longer legally sell and nowhere to get it while the local companies rush to meet the requirements of any new regulations. This would force most if not all vape shops in the state to close their doors, creating hundreds of people without jobs. This can all be avoided by waiting for the FDA to release their set of regulations for the electronic cigarette industry. When the FDA releases these regulations, companies in CT will have abide by them as well as the rest of the country. By jumping the gun and coming out with our own set of regulations we will only cost CT companies money while trying to keep up with the continually changing regulations and wasting CT taxpayer money by trying to rush ahead of the FDA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(F) carry labels disclosing the materials used in the electronic cigarettes and the sources of such materials, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Industry-wide labelling requirements are among the set of regulations that the FDA is currently researching and coming to a conclusion on. While having ingredients listed on the label is already an industry standard, listing the sources of said materials is not only not pertinent from a consumer standpoint, it would serve to make the label even more confusing and hard to read. The labels on 15 and 30ml bottle are small and can only fit a certain amount of information. This should be reserved for important warnings like “May contain nicotine, keep from children and pets” and nicotine strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(G) carry warning labels on the health consequences of inhaling its contents, similar to those warnings required with regard to cigarettes, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until the FDA finishes it’s studies on the health effects of electronic cigarettes, any health implications printed on the labels would be speculation based on whatever scientific studies are out right now. For the same reason we are not legally allowed to say anything positive regarding electronic cigarettes from a health standpoint, we are also restricted in what we can say about the negatives of long term electronic cigarette use. While the vast majority of health studies involving nicotine were arrived at from studying nicotine ingestion through smoking, these studies wouldn’t be an accurate source to base negative health claims. New and pointed studies specifically targeted at realistic electronic cigarette use are needed before a consensus of negative health implications can be made and printed. Putting a scientifically unsubstantiated health claim on our bottle, positive or negative, could leave manufactures open to legal actions. We can only state the FDA’s official stance on this which they have not arrived at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2) the Department of Public Health to adopt regulations to implement the requirements with regard to electronic cigarettes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the recent budget cuts and difficult financial situation in the state on CT, it seems irresponsible for the CT residents to be forced to hold the bill for an unnecessary and unsustainable electronic cigarette regulation. The time, money, and effort could save more lives by being spent on more immediate health issues in the state that have recently had their budgets cut. The FDA is currently addressing everything included in this piece of legislation and more. Through federal taxes, CT citizens are already paying for electronic cigarette research and subsequent FDA regulations. The FDA is better suited to regulate this industry as they can implement an industry standard that the entire country can adhere to. While there are some large corporations involved in the electronic cigarette industry, the vast majority of businesses involved are small to medium sized businesses. While larger corporations can afford the costs of an ever changing regulatory landscape, the smaller businesses involved will be destroyed by the costs. Rushing to regulate this environment is reckless and could crush this industry in CT while forcing countless  CT ex-smokers back to cigarettes and their deadly effects. Not only will this literally lead to the deaths of many CT residents, the preventable and known health care costs of smoking will add an additional tax burden to an already struggling economy. Whether we are talking about lives or money, Connecticut residents cannot afford the unintended harmful consequences of this bill passing. If you have any questions please feel free to contact us. We would love the opportunity to speak with further on this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave Estes and Jeff Burness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pheye Labs LLC&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>select works x DESIGN</title>
      <link>estes.tk/articles/Design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">estes.tk/articles/Design/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/Design/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-is-a-selection-of-my-design-work-&quot;&gt;Here is a selection of my design work.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/Design/&quot;&gt;Pheye Nebula&lt;/a&gt; : Branding project for electronic cigarette asset fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/Design/&quot;&gt;Pheye Labs&lt;/a&gt; : Branding and package design for E-Juice company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/Design/&quot;&gt;Rawberry&lt;/a&gt; : Branding, marketing, web and package design for E-juice company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/Design/&quot;&gt;Cloud 10 Brands&lt;/a&gt; : Package design for E-juice manufacturing company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/Design/&quot;&gt;CT Morgan Horse Association&lt;/a&gt; : Logo re-design for horse organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/Design/&quot;&gt;Little Alcatraz&lt;/a&gt; : Illustration for mobile game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/articles/Design/&quot;&gt;Cloud 10 Brands&lt;/a&gt; : Package design for E-juice manufacturing company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>